SIBASIS MUKHERJEE

Cloud DevOps Engineer

+49-15736584093

mukherjee.sibasis@yahoo.com

sibasismukherjee.github.io



Berlin, Germany



A Multi-Tasking result-oriented and focused consultant with a keen eye on efficiency and quality. Having rich experience in developing and consulting DevOps processes for over 7 years in Banking and Financial Domain. Rich Cloud Consulting experience with enterprise customers on their cloud adoption and acceleration strategies. Developing and Designing fault-tolerant, high-performing and resilient applications and platforms that scale with trending business requirements. Automating event based operation tools that provide deep insight and maintenance of heavy production workloads on AWS. Looking for a challenging and an exciting opportunity to hone my skills on cloud.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Staff Systems Engineer II

Delivery Hero, Berlin | December, 2021 - Present

Owning k8s clusters that are the backbone of all product operations in DH. Leveraging multiple technologies to design and develop infra solutions on AWS.

Cloud Systems Developer

Cloudreach, an Atos Company, Berlin | Sept, 19 - Nov, 21

Solution Architecting and Development of a highly available, fault tolerant and optimized API Platform on AWS. Consult for scaling a multinational automobile giant's Financial Services Group. Providing a robust platform where contributors can develop on cloud. Take charge of DevOps Processes of the platform that can scale to multi-regions spanning multiple continents. Develop tools and libraries that can accelerate SDLC processes on the said API Platform.

Cloud Consultant

DNB, for Tata Consultancy Services, Bergen | Jul, 2017 - Aug, 2019

Took part in a greenfield project to develop a customer centric Banking Application on AWS.Consulting for a major Nordic Bank to develop DevOps Processes for the backend platform.Code all the Infra components from greenfield to production.Drive the Cost Optimization initiative cross project to enhance the architecture further after Go-Live. And drive the Well Architected Review and it's action-points to further strengthen the platform.Drive CI/CD initiatives for multiple projects for both frontends and backends.

Devops Engineer Deutsche Börse AG, for Tata Consultancy Services, Frankfurt | Mar, 2014 - Jun, 2017

Consult for a new Product initiative team to setup automation processes. Develop test-suites and automation pipelines to cover various SDLC's. Leverage open source tools to setup the processes. Support the Operational workloads and Maintain them for bugs and patches..

Professional Certificates







SKILLS

Technical

AWS

Python/JavaScript/Bash

PostgreSQL/MySQL Terraform/ Cloudformation Jenkins, Spinnaker, Concourse

Kubernetes, AWS ECS Docker, Containerd

Datadog, Grafana, Prometheus, Splunk AWS Cloudwatch Atlassian Agile Toolchain

Initiatives

Led Multiple SaaS/ PaaS and laaS Adoption Initiatives for enterprise platforms.

Experience with leading and transforming Modernization Initiatives.

EDUCATION

BTech in Information Technology

West Bengal University of Technology 2009 - 2013

LANGUAGES

English (Native)

INTERESTS

Photography

Climbing & Hiking

Travelling